Rodrigo Carvalho



rodrigos-carvalho@hotmail.com



linkedin.com/in/rodrigokrvalho



https://github.com/Rodrigokrvalho

Summary

Hello, I'm a Software Developer primarily focused on Javascript universe applications web and now mobile.

Since 2019, I have been studying programming and had my first exposure to the field during my Computer Engineering degree. I decided to focus on software development and started learning Java, creating an application called "Assistente de Cozinha" that I published on PlayStore. Since 2021, I have been dedicated to JavaScript/TypeScript, specifically in front-end development using Vue.js and Next.js. I have also worked on some back-end projects using Express and Nest.js.

In 2021, I transitioned my career after working for 6 years in the forestry sector, where I was responsible for evaluating the quality of the entire Eucalyptus forest management process. Currently, I am the technical lead of the development team at EGOS Soluções. I assist in developing processes, participate in technical meetings with clients, and collaborate with management and other departments to align processes and drive improvements.

If you'd like to chat about technology, feel free to connect with me! It would be a pleasure to exchange experiences.

Experience



Development Team Lead

EGOS Soluções

Feb 2023 - Present (5 months)

As a web application developer, I am responsible for the development and maintenance of both frontend and back-end projects using a variety of technologies and techniques.

I lead the architecture of software projects, managing the workflow and providing guidance to the development team.

I am also responsible for selecting technologies and techniques to be applied in each project, as well as conducting code reviews and communicating project status to management.

I conduct technical meetings with clients to understand their needs and provide customized solutions.

Additionally, I am responsible for managing the hiring process and evaluating candidates for relevant skills and experiences that align with our software development needs.

Fullstack Web Developer

EGOS Soluções

Nov 2022 - Apr 2023 (6 months)

I am responsible for building projects that involve the development of databases, APIs, PWAs, and visual interfaces. Additionally, I handle unit testing and application deployment.

I am also responsible for maintaining existing applications, ensuring their functionality and performance, as well as providing training to the team, and documenting the developed projects.

As part of my responsibilities, I participate in team alignment meetings to ensure smooth project progress and the delivery of quality solutions.

Frontend Web Developer

EGOS Soluções

Aug 2021 - Nov 2022 (1 year 4 months)

Responsible for frontend development of web applications:

- Developing interfaces using Vue.js and React.
- Configuring PWAs (Progressive Web Applications).
- Handling data communication with the backend, both sending and receiving data.
- Build unit testing.
- Deploying applications.

Field Technician

Eficiente Solucoes Florestais Ltda

Apr 2017 - Jun 2021 (4 years 3 months)

As a technician, I am responsible for conducting quality assessments and guiding assistants in their execution. I also provide training to new team members.

In the assessments, it is my responsibility to provide feedback on improvements and issues identified during the evaluation.

I also assist the occupational safety team in inspecting vehicles and teams and provide safety training and process improvement guidance to the entire quality team.

I participate in monthly management feedback meetings and share information with other teams.

I also take part in alignment meetings with clients to enhance the processes.

Field Assistant

Eficiente Solucoes Florestais Ltda

Jan 2015 - 2017 (2 years)

As an assistant in quality assessments, I support the technician in conducting quality assessments of various processes of eucalyptus forest management.

The processes that are evaluated include:

Seedling survival at 20 and 90 days

Planting teams

Mechanized and manual fertilization teams

Mechanized harvesting teams

Manual and mechanized herbicide application teams

Manual and mechanized soil preparation teams

The monitoring activities conducted include:

Ant monitoring

Monitoring of areas for weed control

internship

IDEAS

Mar 2014 - Jan 2015 (11 months)

Floristic monitoring of an environmental restoration area at CCRG, and Forestry Inventory

Education



Node, React, React Native

Sep 2021 - Sep 2023

Backend Development:

Express and NestJS frameworks

Key backend concepts: SOLID and Clean Code principles

Frontend Development:

ReactJS and Next.js frameworks

Important frontend concepts: Server-Side Rendering, Client-Side Rendering, Static Generation

CSS preprocessors and styling tools: SASS, ChakraUI, CSS-in-JS

Mobile Development:

React Native framework

univesp

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer engineering

2018 - 2022

Fatec Capão Bonito

Technologist in Silviculture, Management of Forest and Natural Resources

2013 - 2015

Union of diverse knowledge such as seedling production (in vitro and in vivo), nursery activities, forest inventory, soil management, botany, plant biology, management of natural resources, and conservation.

Instituto Politecnico Educacional

Occupational Safety Technician, Health Safety Environment at Work

2012 - 2013

Workplace inspection and evaluation.

Development and implementation of safety policies.

Investigation of accidents and incidents.

Training and awareness of employees.

Maintenance of detailed records and reports.

Collaboration with teams and departments to implement safety policies.

Skills

CSS • Desenvolvimento de front-end • SOLID • Comunication • Problem Solving • Team Leadership • Team Management • Team Building • Teamwork • Requirements Analysis